Guide to the John Nolen pamphlet collection.
Nolen, John pamphlet collection
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
John Nolen pamphlet collection.
6337
17.4 cubic ft.
Pamphlets, brochures, other miscellaneous printed materials.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Pamphlets relating to city planning and affiliated issues collected by John Nolen in the course of his career.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Pamphlets relating to city planning and affiliated issues collected by John Nolen in the course of his career.
SUBJECTS
Subjects:
City planning--Study and teaching.; Community development, Urban.; Highway planning; Housing.; Regional planning.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
A larger collection of work related to John Nolen can be found in the John Nolen papers, #2903
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
The collection has been kept in the order Nolen originally provided, cataloged by number. All un-numbered items have been placed at the end of the collection. We have attempted to provide brief, topical descriptions of the materials within a certain numbered category. Nolen also kept an alphabetical card catalog of his materials. An item can be looked up by subject, author, title, etc., and the corresponding number where the item can be found is provided. This card catalog is available for use, and is listed as box 24.
CONTAINER LIST
- City planning, landscape architecture related bibliographies., 0-1 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
- "American Group of the Societe Des Architectes Diplomes par le Gouvernement Francais" dinner and presentation program booklet., February 4, 1927; 21 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Associations, including American Society of Landscape Architects, American Association for the Planting and Preservation of City Trees, etc., 22 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Associations, including the United States League of Local Building and Loan Associations, World Housing and Town Planning Congress, etc., 22 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- National Highway Association, 22 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- National Housing and Town Planning Council, 22 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Planning Foundation of America, 22 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Town Planning Institute, 25 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Town Planning Institute of Canada, 26 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Information on various housing and town planning associations, committees, meetings, conferences, and conventions, both US and international., 42 (Box 1, Folder 11-15)
- Street and highway safety issues., 42 (Box 1, Folder 16-17)
- International Congress of Cities, International Congress of Local Authorities pamphlets and publications. Also a publication entitled "The Abolition of Slums"., 46 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Programs from various city planning exhibitions., 55 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Information on various planners, including Eliot, Griggs, Adams, and Nolen., 205 (Box 1, Folder 20-23)
- "Royal Ordinances Concerning the Laying Out of New Towns", Spain (ordinances from the 1500s)., 210 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Gardens and parks., 240 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Visions of the American city in the future., 245 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- City planning philosophy and politics., 251 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Education (University lectures, courses, etc.)., 254 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Landscape and city miscellany., 260 (Box 2, Folder 2-5)
- Lectures and personal opinions of J. Nolen., 260 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- City planning miscellany (includes numerous pamphlets on zoning, leisure)., 265 (Box 2, Folder 7-8)
- Creative Discussion, The Inquiry publications., 265 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Farm Cities Corp. of America, Virginia Farms Co., Garden Cities Ass. Of America, America Garden Cities and Town Planning Corporation., 265.17 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- A Christmas for Cities by Gerald Stanley Lee., 286 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- The High School as a Social Centre, by Clarence Arthur Perry., 290 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Suggestions for reading on city planning., 294 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- "New" city planning ideas, planning aesthetically pleasing cities., 305 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Miscellaneous topics in conjunction with city planning, including architects and architecture, housing issues, transportation, and what city planning means., 310 (Box 2, Folder 15-19)
- Effective city planning. Information is similar to that in Box 2, Folders 15-19., 320 (Box 2, Folder 20-21)
- "Design with Respect to Street Tree Planting", by Laurie Davidson Cox, 488 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Planning undeveloped areas (?)., 500 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- City planning and consciousness, reduction of waste, and growth reduction., 505 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Progress reports/history of city planning in the US., 506 (Box 2, Folder 25-26)
- Community organizing, civics., 510 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Civic and political involvement in planning., 512 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- "Suggestions for Organizing Construction and City Development Committees or Departments in Chambers of Commerce", 515 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- "Civic Improvement by Rotary Clubs", 517 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Publicity and advertising, citizen support., 540 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
- Community planning/building., 544 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Public education (in regards to city planning and support)., 548 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- City planning procedure., 550 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Civic Improvement in the Little Towns by Miss Zona Gale., 565 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- City planning legislation., 573 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Villages and small towns., 580 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- City planning and related laws/, 700 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- "Town and Country Planning- the Next Step", 705 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Acts and bills related to city planning., 707 (Box 3, Folder 11-12)
- The legal system and city planning., 722 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- "Enforcing the City Plan", by Frank Williams., 760 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- "The Value of Good Design in Dwellings", by Sir Raymond Unwin., 772 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Information on charges/fees and collecting on services rendered., 800 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Professional charges., 805 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- "The Industrial Survey as a Corrective", by Charles W. Lansing., 812 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Civic surveys., 815 (Box 3, Folder 19-21)
- Topographical maps., 820 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- "A Plan for a Housing Survey", 821 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Surveys and property inventories., 822 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Information on taking surveys., 824 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Industrial surveys., 826 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Survey information., 830 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Modernized public reports., 832 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Geodetic work (triangulations, creating topographical maps, land surveying)., 834 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Relief maps., 836 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Pictorial statistics., 838 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Aerial photography., 839 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- "How to Make a City Plan", a lecture at Harvard., 840 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Technique of city planning reports., 852 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- "Paying the Bills for City Planning: A Plea for Special Assessments for Benefit", 858 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Planning organization (broad planning)., 875 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Competitions., 880 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Financing (?)., 900 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Harvard University., 901 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Architecture, city administration career information., 905 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Landscape architecture., 910 (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Economic research., 920 (Box 3, Folder 42)
- German town planning., 947 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Schools (colleges, universities, summer schools)., 980 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- International schools., 982 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- "Scope of Replanning a City" by John Nolen., 1205 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Economics, debt, finances, etc., 1210 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Social centers., 1210 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Issues regarding municipalities., 1225 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Esthetic planning, building for beauty and permanency., 1235 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- "The Monster City, the Home and the Leaven of Beauty: In Building the City Do Not Forget the Man"., 1240 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- "The Future of American Cities", an address by C.A. Dykstra., 1290 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- "Studies of Relations of Rainfall and Run-Off in the United States"., 1334 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Swamps, wetlands, and wastelands., 1347 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- "Truck Soils of the Atlantic Coast Region", 1382 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Family, social studies, community, etc., 1400 (Box 4, Folder 14-15)
- Class, welfare, and unemployment issues., 1400 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- "A Social survey of Escalante, Utah", 1410 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Class issues., 1415 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- City congestion., 1422 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Population growth., 1424 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- "The Problem of the Landless Man", 1425 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Rural homes and decentralization., 1426 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Housing and house plans., 1427 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Reports on housing and home building., 1427 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Wartime housing., 1428 (Box 4, Folder 25-28)
- Housing problems., 1430 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Subjects related to housing, including low-cost housing, architecture, housing reform, land development and housing, etc., 1430 (Box 5, Folder 2-20)
- Industrial housing., 1431 (Box 6, Folder 1-5)
- Municipal housing., 1432 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Co-partnership housing, housing of employees., 1434 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Employee representation., 1435 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- The Federal government and housing (the controlled community)., 1436 (Box 6, Folder 9-10)
- Housing renovation and modernization., 1437 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- German housing information (in German)., 1438 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Transportation and city planning., 1440 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Public health and sanitation., 1445 (Box 6, Folder 14-15)
- Town planning and sanitation., 1446 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Sunlight and town planning., 1447 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Municipal sanitation., 1448 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Smoke., 1449 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Noise and public health., 1451 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Drainage information., 1452 (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Water and flooding issues., 1454 (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Water systems., 1456 (Box 6, Folder 23)
- Sewage disposal and treatment., 1464 (Box 6, Folder 24-25)
- Garbage collection and disposal., 1472 (Box 6, Folder 26)
- Street lighting., 1476 (Box 6, Folder 27-28)
- Fire waste., 1479 (Box 6, Folder 29)
- Traffic accidents and prevention., 1481 (Box 6, Folder 30)
- Education, including information on public schools and libraries., 1490 (Box 6, Folder 31)
- Leisure., 1495 (Box 6, Folder 32)
- Public employment and welfare work., 1499 (Box 6, Folder 33)
- Laws and government., 1500 (Box 6, Folder 34)
- News articles on broken laws/lawsuits., 1501 (Box 6, Folder 35)
- County laws., 1516 (Box 6, Folder 36)
- Local and state government., 1520 (Box 6, Folder 37-39)
- City managers/city management plans., 1521 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Commission managers and commission management plans., 1522 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Rural government., 1525 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Public administration., 1526 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Advisory economic councils., 1527 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- "Advance Planning of Public Works in the District of Columbia", 1530 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- City planning commissions., 1535 (Box 7, Folder 7-8)
- Public utilities., 1541 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Labor, business, finance and the economy., 1545 (Box 7, Folder 10-12)
- Income, capital, credit, and economics., 1550 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Land uses, including agriculture, industry, and issues on land classification and utilization., 1563 (Box 7, Folder 14-17)
- Building., 1564 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Planning in relation to land values., 1567 (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Taxation., 1568 (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Smaller Profits, Reduced Salaries and Lower Wages by George Rusby., 1569 (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Taxation, financing, budgets, etc., 1570 (Box 7, Folder 22-23)
- Taxation and taxation in relation to land values. Also information on tax reform., 1571 (Box 7, Folder 24-28)
- Assessment and assessment methods., 1580 (Box 7, Folder 29)
- "Federal Aid to the States", 1590 (Box 7, Folder 30)
- Capital expenditure., 1595 (Box 7, Folder 31)
- Zoning., 1600 (Box 8, Folder 1-5)
- Ramifications of zoning, including the constitutionality of zoning, erecting buildings, zoning ordinances, etc., 1605 (Box 8, Folder 6-7)
- Rural zoning., 1609 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Zoning and city growth., 1611 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Zoning and the rehabilitation of cities/neighborhoods., 1613 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Zoning ordinances and regulations and zoning related acts and laws, 1620 (Box 8, Folder 11-15)
- Statistics on zoning and information on zoned areas., 1621 (Box 8, Folder 16-17)
- Neighborhood centers., 1627 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Industrial development., 1630 (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Industry and its relation to transportation., 1633 (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Industry and crowds, including information on defining metropolitan districts., 1635 (Box 8, Folder 21)
- Crowds., 1640 (Box 8, Folder 22)
- Overcrowding., 1677 (Box 8, Folder 23)
- Suburban planning., 1686 (Box 8, Folder 24)
- Housing for low-income groups., 1697 (Box 8, Folder 25-26)
- Apartments., 1702 (Box 8, Folder 27)
- Slums., 1703 (Box 8, Folder 28)
- Greenbelt planning., 1715 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Part-time farming possibilities., 1720 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Unemployment and land cultivation., 1724 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Park and recreational areas., 1730 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Land subdivision., 1800 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Subdivision., 1805 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- "The Acceptance of the New Plats (?)" by John Nolen., 1830 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- "Triumphing Over the Gridiron Plan" by Lawrence Veiller, 1837 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Redesigning subdivisions., 1847 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Boston transportation system., 2000 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Transportation: streets, highways, street signs, naming streets and places, etc., 2050 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- The automobile., 2055 (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Traffic regulations, highways, and laying out roads., 2057 (Box 9, Folder 13-14)
- The automobile and traffic issues., 2058 (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Parking and parking garages., 2059 (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Street and highways issues, including regulations on traffic signs, signals, and markings., 2070 (Box 9, Folder 17-18)
- Traffic surveys., 2076 (Box 9, Folder 19)
- Information on traffic and automobiles., 2076 (Box 9, Folder 20)
- Traffic accident information., 2076 (Box 9, Folder 21)
- Highway design., 2077 (Box 9, Folder 22)
- Construction of roads., 2078 (Box 9, Folder 23)
- Express highways., 2095 (Box 9, Folder 24)
- Automobile size information, for use in road construction., 2103 (Box 9, Folder 25)
- Street width information., 2105 (Box 9, Folder 26-27)
- Multi-tiered streets., 2119 (Box 9, Folder 28)
- Surfacing information., 2121 (Box 9, Folder 29)
- Intersection layout., 2135 (Box 9, Folder 30)
- Establishing future street lines., 2157 (Box 9, Folder 31)
- Arcades., 2161 (Box 9, Folder 32)
- State highway specifications., 2175 (Box 9, Folder 33)
- Express highways, highway routing., 2180 (Box 9, Folder 34)
- Super highway construction., 2181 (Box 9, Folder 35)
- Traffic analysis and road planning., 2188 (Box 9, Folder 36)
- Curb parking survey, San Francisco., 2197 (Box 9, Folder 37)
- The Green Mountain Parkway., 2209 (Box 9, Folder 38)
- Alleys., 2242 (Box 9, Folder 39)
- Highway bridge costs., 2270 (Box 9, Folder 40)
- Furnishing the streets in suburban communities., 2290 (Box 9, Folder 41)
- Rapid and mass transit information., 2350 (Box 9, Folder 42)
- Electric car lines., 2380 (Box 9, Folder 43)
- Rapid-transit subways in metropolitan cities., 2400 (Box 9, Folder 44)
- Railway transportation., 2450 (Box 9, Folder 45)
- Railroads in cities., 2455 (Box 9, Folder 46)
- Diesel power., 2457 (Box 9, Folder 47)
- Transportation architecture., 2480 (Box 9, Folder 48)
- Railroad improvements., 2485 (Box 9, Folder 49)
- Railroad grade crossing., 2512 (Box 9, Folder 50-51)
- Lake ports., 2555 (Box 9, Folder 52)
- Saving waterways., 2570 (Box 9, Folder 53)
- "Making Rivers Work" by John Mathews., 2580 (Box 9, Folder 54)
- Ports and harbors., 2600 (Box 9, Folder 55)
- Fixed cranes at Kearny and Hog Island Yards., 2665 (Box 9, Folder 56)
- World ports., 2790 (Box 9, Folder 57)
- Airport schemes., 2795 (Box 9, Folder 58)
- Removing overhead wires., 2922 (Box 9, Folder 59)
- Real estate and the real estate market., 3014 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Restrictions on land subdivision and building development., 3020 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- "Plotting and Planning of Building Sites" by Professor Sverre Pederson., 3040 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Building lines., 3081 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Limiting the heights of buildings., 3083 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Garden spaces on factory grounds., 3195 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- "Store Buildings and Neighborhood Shopping Centers" by Clarence Stein and Catherine Bauer., 3210 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Subdivision layout., 3230 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Location in a city and property value., 3250 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Lot dimensions., 3275 (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Billboard regulations., 3380 (Box 10, Folder 11)
- "Platting City Areas for Small Homes", by Henry Wright., 3395 (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Architectural Control and Civic Design, by Carol Aronovici & Rollin McNitt., 3420 (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Columns and logs., 3440 (Box 10, Folder 14)
- Suburban homes., 3452 (Box 10, Folder 15)
- Information on The Hermitage, home of General Andrew Jackson., 3456 (Box 10, Folder 16)
- Building control, including information on housing and living conditions., 3460 (Box 10, Folder 17)
- Small concrete garages., 3468 (Box 10, Folder 18)
- Charge estimators., 3469 (Box 10, Folder 19)
- Skyscrapers., 3489 (Box 10, Folder 20)
- Buckminster Fuller's Dymaxion House., 3490 (Box 10, Folder 21)
- Wooden suburbs., 3521 (Box 10, Folder 22)
- The house of tomorrow., 3539 (Box 10, Folder 23)
- Chamber of Commerce buildings., 3560 (Box 10, Folder 24)
- Town halls., 3563 (Box 10, Folder 25)
- Statehouses., 3565 (Box 10, Folder 26)
- Prisons and prison buildings., 3568 (Box 10, Folder 27)
- Development of school grounds., 3570 (Box 10, Folder 28-29)
- Theatres., 3575 (Box 10, Folder 30-31)
- Public baths., 3580 (Box 10, Folder 32)
- Hospitals., 3585 (Box 10, Folder 33)
- Carillon bells., 3590 (Box 10, Folder 34)
- Store entrances., 3600 (Box 10, Folder 35)
- City gates., 3605 (Box 10, Folder 36)
- Municipal markets., 3610 (Box 10, Folder 37)
- Garages., 3611 (Box 10, Folder 38)
- Hotels, lodges, and inns., 3618 (Box 10, Folder 39)
- Home construction., 3620 (Box 10, Folder 40)
- Group houses., 3635 (Box 10, Folder 41)
- Country houses., 3638 (Box 10, Folder 42)
- Small houses for lower income groups., 3639 (Box 10, Folder 43-44)
- The Tullgren Plan for city housing., 3641 (Box 10, Folder 45)
- Tenements., 3644 (Box 10, Folder 46)
- New homes and home designs., 3650 (Box 10, Folder 47)
- Improving small house architecture., 3654 (Box 10, Folder 48)
- Creating better, more efficient homes., 3659 (Box 10, Folder 49)
- Comfort Station., 3677 (Box 10, Folder 50)
- Bandstands., 3681 (Box 10, Folder 51)
- Refreshment stands., 3684 (Box 10, Folder 52)
- Garden plans., 3722 (Box 10, Folder 53)
- Fairs and other outdoor art events., 3724 (Box 10, Folder 54)
- Bridges., 3740 (Box 10, Folder 55)
- Data on various bridges., 3745 (Box 10, Folder 56)
- Fenceposts and wrought-iron work., 3825 (Box 10, Folder 57)
- Memorials., 3830 (Box 10, Folder 58)
- Bronze., 3831 (Box 10, Folder 59)
- Placement and choice of sculptures., 3540 (Box 10, Folder 60)
- Park drinking fountains and memorials., 3849 (Box 10, Folder 61)
- Street lighting and fixtures., 3870 (Box 10, Folder 62)
- Billboard advertising., 3880 (Box 10, Folder 63-64)
- Signs, both street and ornamental., 3882 (Box 10, Folder 65)
- Creating and preserving open spaces in cities., 4000 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Land economics., 4016 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- The preservation of rural England., 4021 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Must England's Beauty Perish?, a plea to save land by G.M. Trevelyan., 4025 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Parks., 4100 (Box 11, Folder 5-7)
- Growth of municipality owned parks., 4105 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Parks as building sites., 4106 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Information on the feasibility and sustainability of parks., 4108 (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Legislation for parks and recreational areas., 4120 (Box 11, Folder 11)
- Camping., 4128 (Box 11, Folder 12)
- "Beauty and Fitness in Park Concrete Work", 4135 (Box 11, Folder 13)
- Park shelters., 4137 (Box 11, Folder 14)
- Park benches., 4141 (Box 11, Folder 15)
- Patio furniture., 4142 (Box 11, Folder 16)
- The Grand Canyon., 4150 (Box 11, Folder 17)
- Public forests., 4160 (Box 11, Folder 18)
- Decorative arts and city planning., 4170 (Box 11, Folder 19)
- An "Assessed Valuation Survey, Bronx River Parkway"., 4183 (Box 11, Folder 20)
- Shore and beach preservation., 4201 (Box 11, Folder 21)
- A guide to Oglebay Park., 4240 (Box 11, Folder 22)
- National parks and forests., 4242 (Box 11, Folder 23-26)
- Municipal parks., 4243 (Box 11, Folder 27)
- State parks., 4245 (Box 11, Folder 28)
- The town common., 4250 (Box 11, Folder 29)
- Outdoor theatre., 4275 (Box 11, Folder 30)
- Public recreation., 4300 (Box 11, Folder 31-32)
- Playgrounds., 4310 (Box 11, Folder 33-36)
- Playground legislation., 4330 (Box 11, Folder 37)
- Information on the value of playgrounds., 4335 (Box 11, Folder 38)
- Planning playgrounds., 4336 (Box 11, Folder 39)
- Airports., 4384 (Box 11, Folder 40)
- City squares as community centers., 4400 (Box 11, Folder 41)
- Cemetaries., 4480 (Box 11, Folder 42)
- Trees., 4800 (Box 11, Folder 43)
- Trees and shrubs., 4805 (Box 11, Folder 44)
- Plants., 4811 (Box 11, Folder 45)
- Boulder Dam., 4844 (Box 11, Folder 46)
- Planting along roadsides., 4860 (Box 11, Folder 47)
- Roadside planning and development., 4875 (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
- Trees for roadside planting., 4885 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Lattices., 4920 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Landscape gardening for playgrounds., 4945 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Cities, designing, and progress., 5200 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- New towns compared to existing cities., 5206 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Housing the Negro., 5230 (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Terminal City: A Triangle of Efficiency., 5315 (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Industrial town development., 5320 (Box 12, Folder 10-11)
- Tennessee Valley Authority., 5340 (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Sir Ebenezer Howard and Welwyn Garden City., 5350 (Box 12, Folder 13)
- "A New Community Plan" by Frank Lloyd Wright., 5550 (Box 12, Folder 14)
- Planning for towns and villages., 5605 (Box 12, Folder 15)
- Planning for small cities., 5610 (Box 12, Folder 16)
- Planning for large cities., 5620 (Box 12, Folder 17)
- "Great Problems of our Great Towns", by Frederick Verinder., 5625 (Box 12, Folder 18)
- The Lineal City., 5642 (Box 12, Folder 19)
- Higher buildings and wider streets., 5660 (Box 12, Folder 20)
- National planning., 6000 (Box 12, Folder 21)
- Regional planning., 6100 (Box 12, Folder 22-26)
- State, city, and town planning., 6200 (Box 12, Folder 27)
- Rural planning., 6300 (Box 12, Folder 28)
- Community planning., 6500 (Box 12, Folder 29)
- Professional landscape architecture., 6600 (Box 12, Folder 30)
- Architecture, municipal planning, and model towns., 6805 (Box 12, Folder 31-32)
- Planning in New England., 6810 (Box 12, Folder 33-34)
- Planning in the South., 6811 (Box 12, Folder 35-36)
- California, 6825 (Box 12, Folder 37-38)
- Florida, 6825 (Box 12, Folder 39-42)
- Illinois, 6825 (Box 12, Folder 43)
- Indiana, 6825 (Box 12, Folder 44)
- Iowa, 6825 (Box 12, Folder 45)
- Kansas, 6825 (Box 12, Folder 46)
- Kentucky, 6825 (Box 12, Folder 47)
- Louisiana, 6825 (Box 12, Folder 48)
- Maine, 6825 (Box 12, Folder 49)
- Maryland, 6825 (Box 12, Folder 50)
- Massachusetts, 6825 (Box 12, Folder 51-52)
- Michigan, 6825 (Box 12, Folder 53)
- Minnesota, 6825 (Box 12, Folder 54)
- New Hampshire, 6825 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- New Jersey, 6825 (Box 13, Folder 2-4)
- New York State, 6825 (Box 13, Folder 5-7)
- North Carolina, 6825 (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Ohio, 6825 (Box 13, Folder 9)
- Pennsylvania, 6825 (Box 13, Folder 10-14)